Indo-Canadian collection
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Indo-Canadian collection
1900 - 1999
F-145
Q106659854
38 cm of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Archives and Records Management Department
The University Archives acquires, preserves and makes available three categories of materials: (1) the official records of the University, including those created by the Board of Governors, Senate, University committees, faculties, departments and administrative offices; (2) materials documenting the wider University community; and (3) historical research collections that promote the teaching and research activities of the University.
The Archives was established within the University Library in 1968 when librarian Liisa Fagerlund was appointed University Archivist on a half-time basis. She continued in this post until 1975 when she left the University. From 1975 to 1978, the Archives functioned within the Special Collections division of the Library. Archival duties were carried out by various library staff members. In 1978, the University Archives was established as a separate administrative unit outside of the Library. Donald Baird, recently retired as University Librarian, became University Archivist and held this position until his retirement in 1990. Jim Ross served as University Archivist from 1991 to 1993, and was succeeded by Ian Forsyth in 1994.
When the Archives was a function of the University Library, the University Archivist reported to the University Librarian. When the Archives was established as a separate administrative unit, the University Archivist reported directly to the University President. The reporting structure changed in 1986 when the University Archivist reported to the Vice-President, Research/Information Systems; in 1990, when the University Archivist reported to the Associate Vice-President, Academic; and in 1996, when the University Archivist reported to the Registrar/Dean of Students.
published
Full
Revised
Title of the collection is based on its contents.
From 1979-1981 the University Archives collected historical information on the Indo-Canadian Community in British Columbia with a view towards acquiring records in this area. The Archives prepared a bibliography, and made copies of relevant material. According to Professor Hugh Johnston, the collection contains a fairly complete set of all articles written up to 1980 about Indo-Canadians in BC. The Archives also acquired some photographs from the community. Since the conclusion of the project, the Archives has shifted its primary acquisition focus away from ethnic collections.
Collection consists of photocopied magazine articles, theses, books, reports, newspaper clippings and other secondary sources about Indo-Canadians. The information is primarily about the Sikh community, but there is also some material on Hindu immigrants. There is one file of photographic prints and negatives.
Collection also contains one file of correspondence with Ray Hundle, who corresponded with the University Archives regarding his research on the possible establishment of a Sikh temple in Golden, BC in 1880.
Material is in Punjabi and English.
The materials were arranged by the Archivist.
Archives and Records Management Department; Photographic materials; Textual records; Community life; Cultural groups; Land, settlement and immigration
SFU Archives created the collection from 1979-1981.
All accessions have been processed as of September 2002. No further accruals are expected.
See also the Indo-Canadian History Collection [Hari Sharma / Interviewer], F-77.
The files are open with no restrictions.
A file list is available.
- SFU Archives Indo-Canadian research project - correspondence, 1979 - 1981; F-145-0-0-0-1 (Archival box - small 145-1)
  published
  Textual records
  Open
- Ray Hundle - correspondence, 1980 - 1981; F-145-0-0-0-2 (Archival box - small 145-1)
- Photographic materials, 1980 - 1989; F-145-0-0-0-3 (Archival box - small 145-1)
- Reference material - authors "A", 1900 - 1999; F-145-0-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 145-2)
- Reference material - authors "A-J", 1900 - 1999; F-145-0-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 145-2)
- Reference material - authors "B", 1900 - 1999; F-145-0-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 145-2)
- Reference material - author Campbell, Michael G., 1900 - 1999; F-145-0-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 145-2)
- Reference material - authors "C", 1900 - 1999; F-145-0-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 145-2)
- Reference material - authors "D-H", 1900 - 1999; F-145-0-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 145-2)
- Reference material - authors "I-G", 1900 - 1999; F-145-0-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 145-2)
- Reference material - author Lal, Brij, 1904 - 1914; F-145-0-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 145-2)
- Reference material - authors "K-L", 1900 - 1999; F-145-0-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 145-3)
- Reference material - authors "M-N", 1900 - 1999; F-145-0-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 145-3)
- Reference material - authors "P-R", 1900 - 1999; F-145-0-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 145-3)
- Reference material - authors "S-Sch", 1900 - 1999; F-145-0-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 145-3)
- Reference material - authors "Sing - Singh, D", 1900 - 1999; F-145-0-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 145-3)
- Reference material - authors "Singh, G - Singh, R", 1900 - 1999; F-145-0-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 145-3)
- Reference material - authors "Sm-T", 1900 - 1999; F-145-0-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 145-3)
- Reference material - authors "W", 1900 - 1999; F-145-0-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 145-3)
- Reference material - parliament debates, 1907 - 1936; F-145-0-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 145-3)
- Reference material - newspaper clippings, 1924 - 1981; F-145-0-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 145-3)
- Reference material - newspaper clippings, 1903 - 1906; F-145-0-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 145-3)
- Reference material - bibliography, 1906 - 1980; F-145-0-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 145-3)